the red button welcome to our live board
meeting
it is number nine I kept miss numbering
them number five for like four weeks in
a row because of how our our YouTube
channel is but we're now on number nine
eight row will be joining us in a little
bit and whoever else wants to join from
the link on the Facebook page it's per
usual we don't have a lot on the agenda
but I put one thing and then we can also
just talk about you know what's going on
in the world safe jet all the other cool
things going on in this space whether
under together tech or not yeah so what
I haven't looked at the agenda what did
you end up putting on there uh well I
when I was listening to an and Adriel
and challenge number who the fourth
person oh um I pictured his name on his
face and not his name but Matus uh
talking and Adriel had mentioned you
guys kind of geeked out on the tech for
a period of time and there was something
a troll said of wanting to get
information on I think which platform to
use or which I don't even know I'm not
under techy that it didn't stick in my
brain but having so I just wanted to
talk about what is what would it look
like to have maybe a few topics that are
theoretically ones we kind of cover ones
have people on board to talk about so
that we could get more of an
understanding of like all of the
platforms are out there and what's good
and what's bad about them you know just
basically a video series that's designed
for that information via semin ated I
don't even know if there's really a use
for it though because of course all
those videos already exist on YouTube
but they're not done in a way that's
like what is out there what's the best
one and even just having that open
conversation about those different
things yeah yeah although that will also
change pretty quick for the tech one
because the one Adriel was suggesting i
would have recommended four years ago
but I no longer recommend so that may be
a periodic one and also like the post I
did today
about a new no code solution you know it
is one of those things that I think
this kind of together tack and project
space will be something more
continuously exploring but yeah I do
like the idea so does that is that still
seems to me to kind of fall under the
thing like oh we need to have an episode
about marketing for projects and then
you're also covering marketing but
you're talking you're doing so but your
your other what about marketing was
solving that wasn't about marketing for
projects that was about the problem with
marketing and how can we make marketing
serve humans better right yes yes it was
marketing in general not necessarily
together text marketing for our projects
and how we do that
and so that is we've tried to have our
roundtables and people just come to them
and then bring whatever is going on at
the moment and we had talked about doing
more of a themed one of Lakeville talk
well marketing this time and seen if
people come and the idea cafe and we do
every other week is kind of supposed to
be that like let's have one I'm
marketing and ask the marketing question
but yeah hobby in like us I guess just
keeping the intention that we keep it
here under the marketing and if you want
to do marketing we have one because we
can keep going back to it and eventually
we'll have one that's better than the
other ones and that we're a month the
best not the newest whatever one's the
better were the best one right could be
the the marketing one or what does
marketing look like under under together
tech but I was more looking into like
brainstorm those topics like what would
those one whenever you and Adriel and
and we're talking about last week was
like it was one topic right it wasn't
four or five six of them and saying what
yeah
and that's interesting because it'd be
interesting to focus both on and maybe
even haven't be separate episodes or the
first half be kind of an evergreen
discussion what do we look for in tech
what's the difference between doing Roy
want to use the fanciest thing the
newest thing or do you need something
with some some history and some backup
you know so yeah kind of an evergreen
discussion and then then maybe
just thinking it might be interesting to
then kind of have okay then what's the
kind of the recommended things if we
have some experts like me and Morticia
on the call who kind of know the space
yeah that would be interesting yeah so
to list out those topics yeah like what
what would they be better since I'm not
in that like cuz there's the tech list
and then the project list right like
marketing and Finance are more of the
project list yes they apply to tech
whereas the tech is also anyone like
let's say you have a tech ID and you're
not as far as long as Adriel and you
what like kind of like a video series
lean startup right where you can watch
this and say okay well this is even
though we don't actually know how to do
it right like actually just having a
conversation on all of those pieces of
like outsourcing right if you wanted to
outsource which who would you hire to
outsource which platform would be use
for that like going through what would
we'd be doing and then you I don't you
know you weren't at the solution raising
for community there was this concept of
breaking a hundred a hundred groups of
100 right to kind of every the plumbing
group would taco plumbing but they're
not they're gonna tackle it as a more
meta problem than like plumbing for this
community and doing something somewhat
like that for tech right of like okay
well breaking it off into this group in
this group and if you're dealing with
marketing there's this free without
breaking off because we can't we resolve
you know like we can't dissipate our
stuff anymore
but having like how can we make this
space useful now it's useful for the
three of us and for other but like how
do we make it even more powerful right
and more that the stuff we're doing in
and of itself is valuable yeah I think
that's interesting also so much of the
advice out there is focused on profit
and I mean a lot of it's you know I
guess it's good that today even a lot of
you know Silicon Valley and stuff
they're trying to do stuff that's more
beneficial they're not quite as profit
they used to be in the past but a lot of
it is focused on find the the the
problem you're gonna solve needs to be
something that people will pay for as
opposed to be based on the amount of
value emojis as opposed to the amount of
value that introduces right which there
is some correlation between profit and
value but it's not a it's not an exact
match we're we're almost focusing on
those things that are not profitable
because of the profitable stuff is being
handled right yeah so how does it go on
Marty's what was a very productive week
on one hand so yeah it's going well my
project is moving along this goes to
really teen and MVP which will be like a
that would be something
finally I did read the specs for the
week elections I think that's bubble
like any before that is one weeks for
initial setup and the first version like
alpha alpha and another week for making
it like more better I think that that
should be enough for like initial for
what's in the stack at least I actually
what you not seen the spec so I don't I
don't know if I miss that or if Adriel
didn't send it my way shared with me the
Google Doc and this is what he showed us
on the reduce meeting so that's it and
it's quite like the first version is
quite simple so I think it's doable
within two weeks unless unexpected about
it is should be double no it's one
person for two weeks you're thinking
yeah I'm really curious what you thought
is the correct time I yeah for some
reason I didn't end up seeing the specs
so I don't know if that's on my side or
fade you I just didn't send it to me yet
but I have to look back and connect with
him and see but from what from the
discussion which I think he gave us a
pretty good outline on the meeting yeah
two weeks sounds about right
I wouldn't disagree with that estimate
Jubilee and I were just discussing I
don't know outline it knows how well
just we're just working through some
stuff figure you know what how to make
this face rifle well it's kind of when
you guys were talking in like there's
all these different projects right now
staff although chained us I just had a
conversation with a different technology
cooperative our chain this morning I
just lecture Jordan hall video where
he's starting the momento it's nothing
what's called momento something on it oh
and I get what I want to do is kind of
bring it back to basics and map it not
with without needing to do the work so
what I mean is and all of those people
have the conversation of how do you do
governance how do you you know how do we
trust each other how do we do those
things and looking at okay if we were
gonna start from scratch that's what we
would need who out there is already
doing these things right we want a team
building up I know we've looked at team
building ones and none of them are
really but like to be able to say here's
what he's just even just a list of what
exists and then start working through
having people maybe that one that like
one of the team building ones coming
together and saying why they like that
one right and having it be I don't know
I'm working through things in my head
right now this is also like the
frustration with all of the the
frustration and beauty that all of the
tech is happening right now and it's
only happening more and more rapidly and
there is this division between like
watching Jordan Hall talk I love Jordan
Hall and I also think all of us people
are very elitist they you know like
they're looking for the top of the top
to work with and although I get why
they're doing that and I'm glad they're
doing that I think there
a big piece of what's out there which is
that we need something that like
everyone can see and everyone can trust
then everything's so complex it up there
and it's hard to know like well while
there's still many of these things and
how does down that compare to polo chain
and how does they like to truly
understand when a tech project comes on
board what is it all the sense making
ones haven't we collection differ from
for reasons for like there's something
that happens behind closed doors it's
the beginning of all of these projects
that is like right why why are they all
working on the same thing over and over
again and us to like what does that look
like right like what is the thing we're
all creating and like what is that since
we're working on our projects
individually and we're bringing them
together to this space to say what are
the common pain points and how do we
solve them somewhat the more met of
conversation of that but maybe this
isn't the place for that like where we
have a very specific you about but
there's something there where the two
can kind of come together and we can
serve our projects while also serving
our bigger mission of creative like I
don't know there's something here I'm
still working yes although that and I
agree I kind of I'm just like I imagined
something like apart from having at
least of everything that's going on out
there and all the projects we just
obvious starting point but immediately
also missing in the talking part like
each and every entry on the list this
project
ABCD and whoever that should immediately
follow with some kind of an interview
like actually talking to the people and
trying to find out some common ground or
possibility of cooperation and just
letting them know that other stuff
exists that was what me what's missing I
think yeah and it makes me wonder
whether it be good or but I don't know
if it's possible with the right
to have a comparison and contrasting
each of these things now of course not
everything I mean you can you don't have
to compare and contrast every single one
but if you put them in buckets and if
they're in the same bucket or I guess an
item could exist in multiple buckets
right then then kind of a compare and
contrast of the other things that are
that are close enough that they seem to
be attacking kind of the same problem
but that also sounds like a lot of work
actually I have an idea for this my my
idea was when while creating a list of
projects and contacting people
responsible for those projects I would
say something hello
I'm creating a list and I described you
on the list such-and-such and if you
want to change something
please come log in and update your
information because I might be wrong and
that would if then some incentives to at
least take a look what was written about
them and hopefully they would feel
compelled to update information about
themselves and by doing that just put
some effort some energy into this this
list to make them maybe read to the
least and get familiar with other
projects on at least something so we
don't have to do it ourselves because I
think owners of projects should be
interested in updating and spreading
information about their project using
our system yeah I think though even if
there doesn't quite get us to the
comparison between the two projects you
know because just too few written
descriptions doesn't actually explain
why these two things are different then
I would out in the description staffing
like this compares two projects project
C which is the sender's
and I wouldn't go as far as saying the
project's is slightly better because and
then project a so you know
oh yeah and often behind not it's not
it's not a better thing but it is that
they're coming at it from different
angles because hollow chain is not is
like not a blockchain but our chain it
does list themselves as a blockchain but
I bet they are trying to solve the same
issues so that'd be something
interesting to say is that all chains
not blockchain right because that would
differentiate it from all the other kind
of ones in that similar space yeah I
guess so there's all the social media
platforms and we don't own any of them
we don't any of the data on any of them
if we all know that and part of what
some of the block chains have tried to
do is say okay well you own your data it
doesn't matter where it's presented you
have the background and you can post it
on Twitter and post on there but you
have you have this and there's somewhat
of an irony that then Dao stack holo
chain I don't know what our chain but
all like probably memento are all sound
like are they creating the backends that
okay even if holo chain disappears all
of the stuff is still there and you can
move it to the DAO stack you can move it
to memento and vice versa or no they're
creating a new thing that's like it's
gonna solve all the world's problems but
only if it's under this umbrella and if
the umbrella fails everything fails and
yes I know we're also kind of doing that
but we're also trying to do it in a way
that it's like and we're transparent so
even if we fail everyone can see and so
it benefits the next one and there's
something about it's beautifully
happening because all these people are
doing it and hopefully somebody succeeds
and somebody creates it and at the same
time it's dissipating that energy and
why this has come up is a couple things
which is this one big conflict that kind
of happened behind around adjacent to
game B between someone who is like Ivan
I have a tech project that I love and
it's my baby and talk to someone who
they thought should be a profession
and they didn't think they'd show up as
a professional man we need to go to
conduct in in and they were really upset
that this person had called their idea
of Aprilaire and I'm like really cuz
don't isn't it like that's what we all
have right is until it's real and they
even when it can be vaporware and so
it's vaporware I'm trying to solve not
like there's something when you have in
science you do a study and then you
publish it there's a lot of information
that's missing because we don't register
null studies if your study didn't come
up come to a neutral or the wrong
conclusion just doesn't get published
right so it's not in there and that's a
very important information that's
missing and I love that usually with
vaporware cuz the idea paper where is
like oh I'm gonna create this and it
never gets created there be a dishonest
component to that right give me your
money and then I have the money never
meant to make it which is I think what
they mean when they say vaporware but
there's also like I have an ID and I
want it to exist and then how much time
and energy I put into it it still goes
into the paper right it still doesn't
exist anymore and the longer and a
longer sphere and so how can we have
people and then there's also this new
person in in game B would stumbled upon
it in a weird way and it's like really
doesn't understand what the NB a--'s and
is trying to make it be game it's like
well where's the leadership I need to
talk to people in charge and we need to
figure out how to get this going and
it's like who are you
and that's something about like it's
like you realize everyone here has a
social media platform because you found
it through the social media he's like
well I can be social media like if you
don't know what game B is you might be
in the wrong crew and he's like trying
to create a social media platform like
so is everybody else and it's like okay
so how can we honor all of that right
that people have ideas that aren't being
done and they can feel really upset that
other people that are these leaders
aren't listening to them why would they
right they're not gonna say like why are
they sitting down with you and not the
like this doesn't make sense
um but the Vapor like there's something
about when if someone comes up with an
idea it could be registered just to say
hey this is something I'm working on
then everyone
yeah that's also my denominator my
domain a mine domain right oh we're all
working on social media how great is
anyone get this know then they're all
vaporware anyway it exists right to have
somewhat of like a register of like work
and I know it exists it's github it's
all these other things like something
about it doesn't matter whether you're
open source whether it's for proper
whether it's gaming your baby that we're
trying to create it what is our purpose
for creating it how do we trust it how
do we know it's gonna be long-term like
some I don't know there's something
there and again it's just working
through it because it's like tension
inside with all this stuff there's
nothing funny about saying my vapor very
vapor where is the best like no - so
just ideas and blueprints maybe and some
I know how to fix it just oh I just need
to work on the documentation and maybe
the cold end yeah and sorry recording
everything is important not only the
good projects that are going somewhere
but good projects that are not going
anywhere and not very good projects
because then the knowledge domain as is
complete and only then we know what has
a chance of working and what was proven
to not work so no one else needs to work
on something that is not going to fly
anyway unless they have a way of making
it right in which cases they're welcome
yeah yeah I I've been in this kind of
space of a lot of people who are trying
to build things that they think will
have a great impact on the world and
that my assessment of most of the
projects is that they were doomed to
fail from the beginning now part of that
is my ego and I do know that a majority
of the people I share my project with
have that opinion of my project
and they still may be right I have not
proven that wrong so yeah I don't know I
was just gonna say I've had a lot of
experience with that in those solutions
ya know and my also like I came in
September in kPa like I gotta solve game
B who do I talk to around here I wasn't
quite like that and people were like
there is none I didn't you felt that I
know how to do this like it's it's there
and now it's like honoring that right
we're all there that's all of us and how
great that this is here that all these
people are here but there's a tension
that happens there right there is no
leader we're all leading and we're all
blind and we're all not like it's a
chaotic beautiful mess and just try to
make some sense of it like watching it
so then watching Jordan halls video and
he's starting this this tech thing and
there was part of it when I was like
parts of it I can see interwoven in it
what we talked about in September where
he didn't have these ideas necessarily
and and then there's what happens in the
game be space between this professional
and this person who had the vaporware
and that he was like well other people
have stolen my ideas and I know I don't
get any credit for them and I don't and
so watching this video with your Jordan
Hall I was like oh how beautiful if a
piece of what I said went into this
right but then if I was also like and I
better get a piece of it too right
because one it's short-haul right like
it's not like he didn't know any of this
stuff but it's like and that's it it's
all interval been together so my issue
and this is my is like he's looking for
more of an elitist how do we get people
together the top top top at this realm
in this room in this room so that we can
create this and then open it up to other
people and I don't think you can create
it without opening up to other people
because otherwise you're creating it for
the Jordan halls and not the
neurotypical and disabled people and
people who maybe gave me a doesn't work
for and but there's something about that
like he what he was saying I was like I
can see part of me will in interwoven
here and that is beautiful and I like
that and at the same time I can see how
from this other person standpoint and
had nothing to join Hall that if that
had happened it'd be like and you
I'd better get a piece of this right
like like what percentage of this is my
responsibility of the truth is you can't
I don't know if you could ever measure
that I don't know I'm Jordan himself is
good would whenever say that he got any
of the ideas for me right um
but it's not about that it's about like
the inter openness of hey I had this
conversation I know it sparked this I
mean it's got in me and I don't know why
that has anything to do in favor where
except that there's like someone has an
idea and they want to hold on to it it's
the best idea and then also if anyone
else it's like I told you about my
social media platform then you made a
social media platform like that's mine
it's like no it's not it's an idea and
so part of what I'm talking about the
paper where I guess like registry is
that you can say it's not about
proprietary us because it is about right
I have an idea for food out cool awesome
that's great did it get made I made a
food app okay why did it succeed or not
succeed right and actually looking at
the ones that exist in are currently in
the field market how do they compare to
each other and then the ones that
they're like I have an idea of great
then we're following it through so we
know if we haven't heard from it in 10
years it's not getting made right like
more just that null like the null
scientists registry which is would be
really useful and I think actually has
started having somewhat of like a
register of we're working on this
project not so other people can't work
on it which is also what I feel happens
under holo chains out stuff it's like oh
yeah someone's on contracts so you don't
need to it's like we don't they the best
people on contracts are they like are
they gonna do better than this new print
like I don't know and so being able to
find who's working in what space who to
contact and then also like so you can
somewhat come together and so or not I
don't know there's something again it's
coalesce Eve so it's not as structured
yeah like in the in the argument debate
tree space several of us were working
for four years before we found each
other it would have been great if we
found each other earlier before our
ideas had solidified I mean we're still
not working on each other's projects
very much because we all think we're
right on these different opinions but we
are learning and growing from me
each other and supporting each other so
that was great to find each other but
yeah there was we had all been on social
media talking about this and searching
on this and just still had not found
each other so yeah so yeah a bit of
talking to interviews could make wonders
maybe
how just imagine game be one the world
and aliens come in and they say we come
in peace take us to your leader
and we say we have no leaders yeah that
sounds like a good beginning of a
sexuality talking about this because I
feel like it means something I mean the
one I'm talking about
yes I don't um so somebody sent me it in
an email
hmm saying he was talking about me at
one at one time point I was so I listed
two I was like he's not talking about me
I'm not in any way involved in this um
and not is where I got it from and so I
think it might be an unlisted video
that's not because because the URL for
memento will be out and in like a
instead a week or two and he doesn't
know the URL yet they call it yoga and
so um it's a that it's not one I looked
at for anywhere else it was someone who
set me at two days ago and I can send it
I can I can post it in our projects page
available you'll be a little disjointed
but I'll post under this post under this
so we know but that makes more sense yes
this is what we took exactly so ghibli
did we explore your topic well I don't
have another topic I was just it's just
like I said it's just like that
working through like what do we do about
vaporware and so what I think I'm gonna
do is like have a conversation with
people who've had an idea that's
vaporware right bit like I don't think
you and Adriel qualify cuz yours isn't
the same
right your guyses is too far along to be
like it's not in that category right you
guys are continuing until you succeed or
fail but like having an idea and then
why didn't it succeed
like even Jim Rudd because when I came
in and like technology it's the solution
and unders I get it
he's like we've been there try that
right it's like what went wrong right
like and so I think I'm what I'm gonna
put up in the Gabey space is hey anyone
who's had anything in the realm of
technology that's failed are you open
for an interview or like a conversation
together of like hey how did it fail why
did it fail maybe there's some spark
from in in my hometown we actually had
for about a year there a monthly video
we caught a fail learn grow and we would
interview local startup founders who had
a failed business or something like that
yeah that's always very is very similar
so yeah I think that would be that also
be very I think that'd be something
people would like to see about doing
business or starting projects they were
about how to fail and what went wrong
because the success story is yeah it's
very nice that someone made all the
right choices or not all the right
choices but enough right choices that he
succeeded and actually did something but
what went wrong is much broader and much
more interesting area so yeah that would
be nice yeah and I know two founders I
mean they weren't in the game B space
but they both took three to six months
off the job like I'm doing now and
started something and then shut it down
that didn't Roy gain traction so I
could I could tap those and if we ever
wanted to I'm not sure if it'd be as
helpful they're not so much the game B
but they were they were hoping to have a
positive impact on the world they
weren't purely profit driven just the
hot weirder harder space to be in cuz
it's like you you need to be profitable
to stay there but you're like I'm here
for the greater good and you still don't
it's still cricket
it's like there's a bigger meta problem
we're not solving here and that's what
I'm talking about like solving that for
vaporware that when somebody has an idea
how do you get the best product out of
it how do you get and I'm just tackling
it Millennials but there's something
about this particular thing in game B of
everyone coming everyone has a project
and some people have valuable actual
projects that are world saving and we
want them out there and there's also
people who have less than stellar ideas
or her per se in my opinion but like
that's my opinion right so it's like
we're how do you know whether there's
merit or not and how do you especially
like it's different because you have the
skill to make your thing so even if
other people can't see your vision you
can see it you can continue moving
forward I'm in a different place where I
can't make anything I have a vision on
except for now I'm starting to realize I
can I can create the idea cafes and the
solution raisins and the things that
aren't tech based and then hopefully
there's tech that comes onboard at some
one time but it was like what about the
tech the people like a lot of time is
wasted coming up with projects that
aren't even putting in that work or
paying someone else to create that work
when they aren't viable to begin with
and yet that's how we all learn like
that's how the agile individual learns
right is like having enough failed
projects because like where does it fail
right and have an idea okay I know for
me just getting a team of people
together to work on it right it's like
okay what's not quite like we decide our
first process raising on Thursday I was
like something failed here I need to
write out something and yet it didn't in
any way like it's it's going to keep
we're gonna meet next Thursday and the
Thursday after but I'm like there's
something miscommunicated between like
Eric and Ramon's and I'm like okay
there's something missing that's
beautiful actually
and it's which I know like I need to
communicate my ideas in a crappy way so
they come back to me and confusing ways
that I can make it a little less well
it's just a little less like a way oh
that's where I went wrong okay I can
agree explain it with just that part of
it and like yeah you put yourself out
there you get better your idea gets
better but there's something about the
vaporware in general that isn't about us
that are individual projects it's about
the world like it's about that these
things come into existence and go out
and the idea itself is good but we don't
all the issues we've been talking
like the marketing and the funding and
how do we make the there might be just
one little thing wrong with the idea but
because we don't have ownership or
transparency or margin like you're not
going to find out and I think like
project raising was a huge is a part of
that because I started saying oh it'd be
great if we had this that I realized oh
we have that that's a project raising
for part of it so like I was thinking a
SWAT team of people that come into your
idea and they think about how to I don't
know the right word here it's not like
improved the idea you don't want to
change the idea too much you want to
kind of evaluate the idea but once again
just because the idea that experience of
going through and learning why there
does it doesn't work doesn't mean you
shouldn't mate you know like slack the
company slack started out as a as a as a
video game maker they pivoted when they
ran out of money if they've never gone
together and made this company to make
this thing slack would exist so yeah so
then I don't I don't even know if we
want to deter to rail someone from that
learning experience but so I so what I
was thinking well that's very similar to
solutions raising so what's what's a
little bit different than solution
raising that says I don't it would be
really interesting to have the SWAT team
come in to help you validate an idea
quicker maybe to accelerate that
learning path yeah it's like it's kind
of the opposite of a project raising
because a project crazy like how do we
help you raise your project and someone
team is like which honestly because it's
like the individual is the one who gets
to choose which one of those things like
I know for me with the idea of together
tech and a technological operative and
all the ideas of how tech saves us I'm
not stopping unless somebody kills me or
somebody saves the world like there is
no stopping yes every project can fail
every relationship can visit ever I'm
not stopping unless someone breaks it
for me
unless someone
actually points out the flaws in like
actual system and it's not about
convincing it's like I have to see the
flaw right that it's big enough that
it's like my life's work is it's not
here cuz what's working isn't working
like what's out there isn't working I
can see something better and so I'm
gonna keep trying to work towards it
until it's there or it's not and I don't
want to take that away from other people
and yet I do cuz I want people to take
that away from me I don't anymore but
before when I was all alone I was like
somebody that needs to come join me or
like break this for me cuz I'm gonna
waste my life here I mean I would I
would love if someone would come in and
give me proof that reason score will not
provide as much value as I think well
not provide a sufficient amount of value
I'm pretty sure it won't provide as much
value as I think it will but still will
be enough value to spend more time on it
but I could be wrong I could get a year
down the path and realized that it
doesn't matter how good this is at
making the truth obvious that if no one
if if the level of effort to get that
level of learning is too high then
people will not do it there's not enough
money to pay there's there's definitely
a chance of there being a wall on why
this idea won't work but yeah until I
have irrefutable proof of that I'm gonna
still bang my head against the wall
which I have been doing every I've given
up like four or five times but a week
later I'm like okay what's my next big
idea and I said oh this idea won't work
until I can have this truth seeking I I
keep coming back to it because every
other idea it would be so much better if
I had this this first core thing done so
but yeah it would be nice if someone
would sit down long enough and and
actually prove not just say oh I don't
think that's gonna work or here's why
you know cuz a lot of times they'll
bring up and they're just not like
they're not like absolute blocks they're
just like walls that I that we have to
figure out a way over but they're not a
reason to stop so yeah yeah yeah so I
wonder whether it's getting to that spot
faster or just a group of people to come
around
and a lot of the ideas it's just
validation although it doesn't work with
my idea because I keep you know I keep
trying things out and no one grabs on to
it but I keep thinking it's like well it
just means I'm not explaining it right
but maybe that's not it right it could
be that well it's yeah coming together
like it is something that is and this is
what I'm talking about I don't like the
vaporware and everything else like it
seems like the people as long as you
hold the vision you're gonna keep moving
forward with it and thank God at the
same time there's certain like I look at
the idea there's certain ideas I've
become across and game being that I'm
like this is in no way a solution hmm
the idea itself and I think separating
the idea from the person is actually
really powerful to say okay well am i
trying to knock her Bentley's feelings
or my trying to her Bentley's feelings
has nothing to do with the idea right
versus the idea itself and then also can
I understand it to be able to critique
it anyway right I'd like to be able to
understand how you think this should
work before I'm like oh back at work
there's no way we could have you know
great sense making
um which is what I'm coming up with in
processor AZ and it's like well there
couldn't possibly away ten thousand
people can come together create a
project so we'd like have this what's
the word like a narrowing down process
like that's not actually what I'm try to
say I actually think we can create
something with ten thousand people or I
wouldn't be doing it we just aren't
there yet and so it's like like I could
see the vision enough that I will keep
moving in that direction and there's
that like what I was trying to say that
I didn't get to was the person the ideas
I've heard from people then I don't
think our solutions I don't know if I
would look at them differently and see
the beauty of let's say they came from
Jordan Hall right like what if they came
from a different person and or what if
this person who's maybe not the best at
communicating the idea but the idea is
really good what if somebody else was
able to communicate this idea
like what if you had you know Russell
Brand explained the suite yeah
then I'd definitely be behind right like
what's not gonna go by Russell forensics
way and so like that I don't I don't
know what I'm going with that but so
it's just thinking I have have we seen
any ideas that we knew upfront could not
be successful and then do you think we
could have proved it and saved some
resources do have you seen any that you
know for a fact wouldn't have worked yes
but and I did try and the person wasn't
open to having a conversation now that's
from my side right because from their
side they're like you didn't look at it
enough you didn't like really look at it
I'm like I did like there's if part of
it is this person couldn't have a video
conversation I cannot yeah right so it's
like when you have an actual
conversation different different
communication stops yeah and so it was
like that there's just not a solution
here and every my opinion and so and
then there's other ones where I'm like
oh I love this 90% and those are the
ones I actually want to deal with right
like like here's the 10% I don't like
and it's for you to accept it or fix it
right like it's not you don't need to
take on my little view just here's why I
don't think blockchain here's why I
don't think you know but that's gonna
happen right and that is also this space
because it's like we're trying to solve
things for other people instead of
solving them for ourselves because of
course that's what gaming is and we have
to do it that way right like you have to
put yourself in other people's shoes and
say how do they make decisions on
reasons that you can create reasons for
but they will use it at the same time if
there was a way to like bring it from
the ground I've no idea how we do that
freezes right but from the ground up of
like how do you and the closest will be
tomorrow we do the solution yeah
solution raising it's like how do we get
our information how do we what could
that look like with 10,000 people and
$100,000 but having again well yeah
there are some ideas that that can come
up that way and the challenge with
reason scores it's kind of like
inventing the light bulb you wouldn't
have gotten there unless you try it out
some different materials like they you
know they literally tried a thousand
different materials tell it was a piece
of metal from a folding fan that ended
up having the right thing to wear it
worked for thirteen hours and that was
the success we got like over the last 13
hours can you imagine having light bulbs
they don't last that long so yeah
there's there are different groups some
of them some ideas some things take a
big R&D cycle and some of them it's like
oh we we know we know kind of what we
get net that the question is how do we
make the it an interface to where the
people can use it and then it's then
it's a lot of really good input from
people so like for the reason school
idea although I'm going off tangent I
got to figure out how to get the math to
work and then after that there's tons of
ways to represent it and I and I need
people's input on how do you how do i
display this information in a way that
is meaningful and useful to you and how
do I collect it from you in a way that's
not you know dragging glass across your
scanners which is what it turned out
it's like I'm gonna have to like hire
somebody because it's too boring for me
to do or too painful so yeah that's
different yeah different ideas do
definitely have different kind of
investment levels but yeah so I was just
thinking is there is there a way I could
really help cuz there's like you know
like I have some concerns about
Adrienne's idea that he's not here to
defend himself from but you know I'm
still gonna support him on that and I
don't know none of them are like oh you
can't do this because his idea I think
has some has some definite possibilities
there's just some risk that you have to
mitigate like well you know will he have
enough funds to get it produced if but
you know and that's why it's really
important that when more to she and I
are helping him develop this that we're
making sure that what we're doing will
get him to a point where he can get some
traction right there's a lot of features
we could
we could put in and if we were just game
a software developers we'd be like oh
there's a feature yeah we'll put it in
but we kind of have a bit of
responsibility to say we're happy to do
this but are you sure that this is
getting you closer to funding support of
you know or is this just a nice-to-have
feature and that's why I kind of I am
very careful about doing development for
anyone in this space even donating time
all right it's poor like I don't want
them to pay me for something unless I
really know that it's going to be
successful that is yeah it is morally
not come to two percent obvious because
oh I'm not sure how to express this but
if we are going to and the idea is to
create something that is not they may
basically so we are not doing this for
profit and on the other hand there is oh
it's complicated I want to say something
different I think so I would say also
something something something different
I did not see any one particular idea
that I would be sure it's not going to
succeed in any way possible it's like I
haven't seen anything that I would know
is going to fail completely same with
your projects and I might have some
reservations or some ideas what would
need to be done differently but I don't
think I can state them before eyes
before we can show something that is
working and before something exists that
can be actually improved because it's
hard to
Fiori make a theory about what we can
improve when there is nothing physical
to improve yet so I would well
I always prefer to code something and
have it working and then improve it once
it's there so there was feedback
relating to something that people
actually use and are able to see as
opposed to something that they think
it's not though it work because
something so yeah practice first yeah
and sometimes a small bit of development
or or work and get you to that
validation mind yeah so I'm just
thinking through whether there's any I
mean I've given lots of people advice on
ideas and sometimes I was helpful and
sometimes I really wasn't yeah I don't
know if there's a I mean yeah I I think
that there probably is a there's
probably something there that we could
figure out how to improve the efficiency
in that in that area of taking idea to
kind of prove point yeah and then
there's also like when you have an idea
it's also sometimes in its infancy
especially when there isn't a thing to
critique and improve of like all the
emotional stuff that comes up when
someone's someone's critiquing it and no
we know that you're capable of handling
that right in any any moment but was I
kind of like three conversations for
this favorite where thing like I want
people who had the idea never got it
made those are the people in game B I'm
the best idea why aren't you guys giving
me money and asking to make this for me
that's me I know what it's like and then
people who've made it and it's a
beautiful product but they shouldn't
have users right the marketing was off
or and then people who had a product had
users it was working but it wasn't
financially sustainable right
that would just was able to last a long
time and then what went wrong but I'm
gonna put up a post in game B just
asking for people to have a conversation
saying awful one on one on one and then
having the conversation I would why did
it fail but they'd be very interesting
to see and since you kind of see
yourself as one of those people if you
need someone to interview you about your
experience then I can probably do that
if you want to be a subject of one of
those meetings yeah we'll see because I
don't I haven't failed Bentley no yeah
but you did that emotional journey where
yeah where we come in with a great idea
and then it's like oh I got a my egos
take a couple bruises and then
interesting story in that space so yeah
and I you know I could probably talk
about mine yeah the only yeah I'm trying
to think I guess the reason scores not
there yet to be in that conversation to
be a value I mean I the one other
project that I did that was personal
that I ended up really shutting down was
just a podcast and those because I was
way too vague on the topic so no one
really ever listened to it but there's
not a lot of learning there so I I know
there's like I'm gonna I have yet to
have a one-on-one conversation with Jim
but I'm in approached him about this one
cuz I'm like I want to know like if you
don't think technologies the answer what
was the failure what didn't work and
what was and yet his his opinion I don't
if he's open to that and then it is I
know there's a bunch of people in there
and then I do want a bunch of people
like me who have the like vaporware idea
write some paper bricks it has it gone
away it could this is not made it's not
financed so it's not even like a team
making it necessarily right but it's
still not failed because I'm still
holding on to it I haven't let it go
so all of those right like people who
are like I have the social media
platform like we take a step back and
realize that no you don't cuz no one
does because you don't have your friends
family you need millions of people is
not the point of a social media platform
anyway that's not like getting people
have the idea and have a conversation of
what's broken here why can't we work
together on one especially a social
media or team building or any any of
this this stuff ends there's something
broken between you that's an individual
I like to create I like to create in my
room yeah I can't communicate it to the
world and now I'm enjoying creating with
people but we all like kind of creating
by ourselves and with people we don't
know how to like crew we don't
definitely on a grave 10,000 people but
like what the difference between Chris
solving it alone in your bedroom and in
your minds and solving it with people
and I'm in that stage and I needed to
get there through game B I came into the
space solving it by myself and I'm like
okay but now I gotta solve it with
people and like getting into that as a
more meta and not really if something is
broken
I'm sure if it's the right word to use
because there is something needed and I
think technology is a big part of the
answer but there's missing a piece in
this the way I see it the images I have
now are like neurons that are separate
and they need something to realize they
are part of the network and connect
that's the one thing and the second
thing is when you had all the static
electricity in the cloud in order for
the lightning to happen there is some
condition that needs to be present this
will be there so there is something
missing but not necessarily something
broken because something broken or imply
that there is nothing we can fix but I
think it's more like there's something
we can add to the equation in order to
make this all work to make the
connectivity happening that is exactly
what I meant by this is broken there is
a piece missing
there's something here that's not quite
working and I don't mean it yeah thank
you yeah and and do you think your
phrasing it mostly is why why can't we
coalesce and work together because I
mean I see a lot of that but is that I
just want to make sure that that's your
core thesis I don't know what the core
it's it's literally I can save the world
alone in my bedroom I can't communicate
it with the rest of the world I'm now
encountering all these other people who
also have saved the world alone in their
bedroom what is missing to get us to
come together go back to square one and
work you know what I mean create like
what is the missing piece
I liked the neuron because it's like
we're all firing neurons but the reason
to know there's a neurological system
right so that's just pain that's just
like send out a signal that's broken
it's that is broken and it's like yeah
so there's something missing and yet the
neuron just keeps firing at them and
then it does find its pathway and actual
biology but yeah like there's something
missing in it too that I'm trying to get
out and yet it's it's brand-new and it's
like something that's no one solved
because the point is you what do you
mean you want to work for something from
the ground up like you just build it and
it fails or succeeds you find a small
group of people and you build it or it
succeeds like it's Aria fails or
succeeds it's like no there's something
here it's just like almost ready so the
point is not to become the biggest
neuron in the neighborhood the point is
to be the right neuron in the right
place and connected to the right other
neros mm-hmm yeah have a connection at
all because all right I mean you know
excited yeah so I'm in part of a group
that has six or seven developers having
some of them are researchers and stuff
all working on some sort of debate tool
that we all have our own tools we're not
able to coalesce around the single idea
and I don't know if that's a I mean that
seems to be
my heart it'd be a feature but yeah
because you'll disagree about the some
core idea how it should look like how it
should work like oh we are hitting it
slightly different benefits so like for
this example they and we're almost out
of time I guess they want a system that
models several of them wants a system
that models real-world discussions like
if two people are sitting at a table let
we need to log down what they're saying
and then work through it and I guess I
do agree on that some instance but my
yeah so I do have a slightly different
thesis on what the problem is and what
the solution is and they have slightly
different concepts of that but we are
learning from each other because we'll
talk about okay this is this is our
difference in opinion on trying to think
about the most recent one we're talking
about context and debates and stuff like
that and so we're throwing on different
definitions of stuff like that and yeah
they'd recently changed my mind on
something where I might want to
implement it and reasons Corwin before I
was reticent about it
so so I guess part of the process is
working through and coming to an
understanding of a shared understanding
of the problem and the solution weird
okay cool weird question it's yo data
like back-end data they got structure
compatible with theirs so no but we as a
group we are working on building a
shared back-end
oh well mostly very on the front end and
then I diverged from that so
I'm asking because I have this one of
the like enlightening moments you know
when I participated so discussion about
[Music]
buck and versus front-end separation as
in the data can be like all the same one
scheme out one structure one later
established and like we know the data is
correct it's coherent and it's there and
we can have variety of tools and
interfaces to this data so and that is
very powerful idea because it means it
really moves a lot of stuff that
previously is you know for each project
you need to create a front-end to show
to people and have users and and stuff
and you need to have a back-end and to
be full of makeup so having a shared
pool of established like I would remove
like the effort for everyone and it can
be awesome yeah so that that is the
first place we're going to collaborate
because supposed to most of our
differences are in the front-end I think
well it looks like we're about out of
time we are and so you can wrap it up
here this is our to be you does anyone
have a question they want to do next
week for the idea Cafe that we would
like to answer for our projects my brain
keeps having issues but you are Nesta do
you have a question for us to answer for
our projects for idea cafe next week and
tomorrow we're doing a instead of a
project round table we have a solution
raising during that time period on
sense-making
on media and information I'm actually
doing three within basically a week
Wednesday was media and entertainment
The Saturdays media and information and
then we're doing social media on
Wednesday because the next one steaks I
kind of left that up I was like yeah
that actually seems
important considering that's kind of
what weren't I'll try to tackle or a lot
of people are trying to tackle and
really well you have an access to the
chat for this because I was not reading
or nestos comments yeah you can always
just you can come in here one there in
Facebook so they're in our Facebook oh
oh oh that's right there on the package
okay and you can always come back to
this link it'll be open you can't you
can't put yourself in here so you can't
see yourself but you could read the
comments or always like a giant I'll
reply on Facebook yeah I'm sorry again
for not reading the comments but did he
I don't see a question here so thank you
it would be great if you guys could take
a look at era org okay I'll put us up
here great and if you want to if that's
your project or nest if you want to post
it in the Facebook group and ask for
feedback to be fine
such as well Steve moon same the SWAT
team yeah do you want the SWAT team or
the port that improve solution or the
project crazy
all right well say goodbye for now and
next week we're back with an idea cafe
we don't quite know what the question is
yet and the week after board meeting and
then next next Saturday we'll be back
with our roundtables and so goodbye
together check community